### **OGUNDIRAN OLANREWAJU OLARINRE**

No 62, Aru zone 1, Area 3A, Olodo, Ibadan.

+234-807 402 1326 olanrewajuogundiran@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

# **COMMUNICATION AND LANGUAGE ARTS GRADUATE WITH**

### **DIVERSE EXPERIENCE**

Apex aiming communication graduate with the zeal for effectual exploits of varied communication aspects to attain the optimum organizational vision and mission. Work experience has afforded an opportunity to perform numerous tasks providing room for dexterity in accomplishing goals while displaying the ability to multitask in-between set fruitions.

I am a high achiever who desires a challenging position in an establishment where my education, skills, knowledge will be effectively utilised, aiming at job satisfaction and self improvement in order to achieve the organisational and individual objectives.

#### **SKILLS**

**IT Skills:** Knowledge of Corel Draw, Adobe PageMaker, MS Office (Word, Excel, Power Point, Access), Explorer, Internet Utility, PC Fundamentals.

**Personal Skills**: Optimum communication capacity, Excellent problem solving competence, Ability to work with little or no supervision, Impeccable usage of English Language, Target-Driven, Innate teamwork capability, Research Skills.

**Soft Skills:** Attended a seminar organised by MacNel Consult Limited, University of Calabar, Calabar, Cross River State, on "Work Ethics, Customer Satisfaction, Public Speaking, Negotiation and Marketing Skills" (February 2014).

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **English Language Tutor**

VELOS SECONDARY COMMERCIAL SCHOOL, CROSS RIVER (NYSC). 2013-2014

Played a vital role in inculcating both academic and moral lessons in students of the institution.

# **Key duties:**

- Served as English language instructor.
- Ensured engagement of Students in both oral and written English.
- Conducted and Supervised examinations for the institution.

# **Voluntary On-Air Personality**

CROSS RIVER STATE BROADCASTING CORPORATION, IKOM 89.7FM. 2013-2014

Added practical knowledge of unparalleled presentation and communication of intriguing broadcast programmes.

# **Key duties:**

- Acted as Sports Analyst.
- Assisted with other delegated responsibilities.

### Writer

INFOBASE360 BLOG. 2014-2015

Harnessed the strengths of online media platform to disseminate breaking and incisive news stories.

## **Key duties:**

- Contributed sports articles to the medium.
- Edited blog contents.

## **Language Arts Instructor**

GLOBAL SCHOOL OF SCIENCE, IYANA CHURCH, IBADAN. 2015-2018

Utilized sophisticated training techniques to efficaciously instil the nitty-gritty of English Language in students thereby recording quantum students' performance level.

# **Key duties:**

- Adeptly executed assigned teaching tasks.
- Provided professional insights as assistant press club Coordinator.
- Conducted internal examinations.

Supervised external examinations.

# **Use of English Tutor**

QUEST TUTORS, IYANA CHURCH, IBADAN. 2018-2019

Enhanced UTME candidates' proficiency in English through thorough teaching thus culminating in their academic upward mobility.

# **Key duties:**

- Practically inculcated knowledge of lexis, structure, reading comprehension etc. to aid students' understanding.
- Periodically set tests to assess their improvement.

### **EDUCATION**

# MA Cultural and Media Studies (In View)

UNIVERSITY OF IBADAN 2018-2019

- Studies the techniques involved in the deciphering of latent and manifest meanings in media production.
- Examines Africa's experience in the broad and global development of the New/Social Media and cyberculture.
- Comprehends the policies governing print, electronic, pubic relations and advertising in Nigeria and their implications for development.
- Gains insight into indigenous means of communication in relation to global purview.
- Carries out research in Media, Communication, and Cultural Studies.

# **BA Communication and Language Arts (Second Class Upper Division)**

# UNIVERSITY OF IBADAN 2008-2012

- Studied divergent modes of communication thus grasping vivid details and productive angles as regards communicative acts of reading, writing, listening and speaking.
- Assimilated professional subsets of the course: Advertising, Public Relations, Journalism, Corporate Communications, Technical Report Writing etc. and their expertise at delivering a communication masterpiece.
- Conducted communication based research to evaluate relational effects of the media on the populace and its connectivity with personal societal motives.

# **Senior School Leaving Certificate**

IKOLABA GRAMMAR SCHOOL 1998-2004

## **OTHER INTERESTS**

Reading: I regularly engage in this to learn new ideas.

Writing: This expressive act strengthens my ability to think and creatively recreate insightful thoughts.

Watching soccer: I regularly watch soccer matches to learn the essence of team work in success.

Surfing the net: Through this, I keep up-to-date information repertoire.

Meeting people: I understand the importance of interpersonal relationship in a workplace, ergo, I like mingling with diverse individuals.

Researching: Via researching, I get acquainted to ways of drawing inferences from facts to further establish new ones.

### **REFERENCES**

Available on request.